gardenerschoice.com 2019-03-29

# Privacy Policy | BAM-FX

### Purpose

It is the established policy of the BAM Agricultural Solutions Inc. and BAM-FX ® to respect and protect the right to privacy of our visitors and to be compliant with all applicable laws and best professional practices pertaining to the same.  

### Who we are

Our website address is: [https://bam-fx.com](https://bam-fx.com/).  

### What data do we collect?

We collect the data necessary to service our website users. This data includes contact information and service preferences, and other data related to the conduct of the business of BAM Agricultural Solutions Inc. and BAM-FX.  

### How and why do we collect it?

**Analytics**

We use MonsterInsights WordPress plugin that provides Google analytics services.

Website users who don’t want their data collected with Google Analytics can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout

**Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

**Comply with Law**

To comply with legal obligations, as part of our general business operations, and for other business administration purposes.

**Cookies**

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

**Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

**Forms**

  1. **Contact Forms**

We keep contact form submissions for a 1 year period for customer service purposes, but we do not use the information submitted through them for marketing purposes.

  2. **Email Marketing Opt-In Forms**

All email marketing opt-in forms used on this site, such as popups, floating bars, inline-forms, and others, require explicit consent from users before adding them to our mailing list.

This is done with either:

    * A checkbox that user has to click before opt-in; or,
    * Requiring double-optin to your email list

Information gathered is used strictly for that purpose for which it was intended. We do not share the information submitted on an opt-in form with any third parties.

Subscribers to email marketing my unsubscribe at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email.

**Marketing and Promotions**

For marketing and promotional purposes, such as to send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or to otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest you, including information about third party products and services.

**Media**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

**Prevent Misuse**

Where we believe necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or violations of our Terms of Service or this Privacy Policy.

**Provide our Services**

To provide you the services we offer on the website, communicate with you about your use of the website, respond to your inquiries, provide troubleshooting, and for other customer service purposes.  

### Who do we share your data with?

Your data is shared with third parties who help us to analyze data, follow-up with you and provide better customer service to you including:

  * Google Analytics: https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites
  * iContact Email Marketing Software: https://www.icontact.com/legal/privacy
  * JotForm Online Form Builder: https://www.jotform.com/privacy/

### How Long Do We Retain Your Data?

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

While laws like the GDPR have “right to erasure,” we are not required to erase records needed for other aspects of our business such as: charges disputed by a customer, tax audition, or for other legal concerns. [View Terms of Use >](https://bam-fx.com/terms/)

We keep contact form entries for six months, analytics records for a year, and customer purchase records for ten years.  

### What rights do you have over your data?

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

**GDPR User Data Request**

Should you wish to have data access, have data forgotten or data rectfied in comments, posts and our database, please submit a request using the form on this page: <https://bam-fx.com/data-request-form/>.  

### Where do we send your data?

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service, such as Askimet: https://automattic.com/privacy/  

### How do we protect your data?

BAM Agricultural Solutions Inc. and BAM-FX® maintain both hard copy and web based data entry form as applicable to the conduct of the business of BAM Agricultural Solutions Inc. and BAM-FX. Online form data is collected and transmitted by secure means. Online form submissions are stored in secure databases with limited access and any sensitive information is encrypted for another layer of protection. We periodically update our membership database using a variety of means to ensure delivery of all publications/correspondence and to better model the demographics of BAM Agricultural Solutions Inc. and BAM-FX®.

Users’ data is also protected by our SSL Certificate (Strong SHA2 & 2048-bit encryption), McAfee SECURE (which scans and certifies our website), Website Security Essentials (malware scan and removal), Google Re-Captcha (two-factor authentication), and staff training in data protection.  

### What data breach procedures do we have in place?

We are required to report certain types of data breaches to relevant authorities within 72 hours, unless the breach is considered harmless and poses no risk to individual data. However if a breach is high-risk, then we must also inform individuals who are impacted right away.  

### What third parties do we receive data from?

We may receive data from:

  * Facebook Advertising when using the Facebook pixel placed on ads in Facebook and/or Instagram.  
Privacy: https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation  
Cookies: https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/
  * Google Analytics
  * iContact Email Marketing Software
  * JotForm Form Builder

### What automated decision making and/or profiling do we do with user data?

No automated decision making occurs on this website.  

### Who on our team has access?

Administrators on our team have access to the information you provide us to support you.  

### How do you contact BAM Agricultural Solutions Inc. and BAM-FX®?

Individuals may contact BAM Agricultural Solutions Inc. and BAM-FX® if you have concerns about privacy. Individuals may contact BAM Agricultural Solutions Inc. and BAM-FX ® to opt-out of any or all hard copy and/or electronic correspondence not explicitly related to requests for services.

BAM Agricultural Solutions Inc. and BAM-FX® may be contacted by mail at the following address:

**BAM Agricultural Solutions, Inc.**  
190 NW Spanish River Blvd., Suite 101  
Boca Raton, FL 33431  
USA

by email at: [info@zerogsi.com](mailto:info@zerogsi.com)  

### Updates

BAM Agricultural Solutions Inc. and BAM-FX® will update this policy, post notice of the changes and post the updated policy to the BAM-FX® website.
